let's suppose that you have two finite
sets A and B and you want to find the
cardinality of their Union a union B you
might think that the cardinality of the
Union is simply the sum of the
cardinalities that is that the
cardinality of a union B is the
cardinality of a added to the
cardinality of B but note that elements
in the set a intersect B have been
counted twice in this computation once
in a and once in B so we must remove one
copy of the cardinality of a intersect B
so the cardinal it of a union B is equal
to the cardinality of a plus the
cardinality of B minus the cardinality
of the intersection of A and B an
alternative is to think of the Union in
three separate pieces so that the
cardinality of a union B is the
cardinality of a set minus B plus the
cardinality of a intersect B plus the
cardinality of B set minus a